Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're talking a little bit about food and about your health.
我是Catherine，今天我们聊一聊食物和健康。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to take a look at our favorite maybe kind of food.
今天我们要看看我们可能最喜欢的某种食物。
We're taking a look at the fast food, all these yummy but not very healthy types of
我们要看看快餐，这些美味但不太健康的
food.
食物。
Yeah, we are.
是的，我们确实要聊这个。
So let's listen to our dialogue and when we come back we'll be talking about what some
那么让我们先听一段对话，等我们回来后会讨论其中一些食物
of these foods are and what some of the phrases you've heard mean.
以及你听到的一些短语是什么意思。
I'm hungry.
我饿了。
Let's order up something to eat.
我们点些吃的吧。
Okay.
好的。
Maybe we can order a soup and a salad from the restaurant down the street.
也许我们可以从街那头的餐厅点一份汤和一份沙拉。
I was thinking of getting a hamburger, fries and a chocolate sundae.
我想点一个汉堡、薯条和一个巧克力圣代。
You eat too much junk food.
你吃太多垃圾食品了。
That sort of stuff clogs up your arteries and is very high in cholesterol.
那种东西会堵塞你的动脉，而且胆固醇很高。
Well I never seem to gain weight so I don't mind.
嗯，我好像从来不会发胖，所以我不介意。
It's not only about getting fat or not, it's about being healthy.
这不只是胖不胖的问题，而是健康的问题。
You could really have some health problems later on.
你以后真的可能会有一些健康问题。
How about pizza or maybe some fried chicken?
披萨或者炸鸡怎么样？
Better yet, let's order some hot dogs.
更好的是，我们点些热狗吧。
You're a lost cause.
你真是无可救药了。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at language takeaway.
现在让我们来看看语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
So first up on language takeaway is a very unhealthy food.
语言要点的第一个是一种非常不健康的食物。
It's called a chocolate sundae.
它叫做巧克力圣代。
That's right.
没错。
We wanted to order hamburger, french fries and a chocolate sundae.
我们想点汉堡、薯条和巧克力圣代。
So chocolate we know that this is the flavor that comes from cocoa.
巧克力我们知道这是来自可可的味道。
But what is a sundae?
但什么是圣代？
Well basically a sundae is a kind of ice cream dessert.
基本上圣代是一种冰淇淋甜点。
It comes in a cup or a bowl and it's usually vanilla ice cream with chocolate sauce and
它装在一个杯子或碗里，通常是香草冰淇淋配上巧克力酱，
then oftentimes a cherry on top.
然后经常在上面放一颗樱桃。
So as you can see the word is pronounced exactly like the day, sundae, but it has a different
所以你可以看到这个词的发音和“星期天”完全一样，但结尾拼写不同。
spelling in the end.
结尾拼写不同。
S-U-N-D-A-E, sundae.
S-U-N-D-A-E，圣代。
So this is a chocolate sundae.
所以这就是巧克力圣代。
So when you see this spelling, a sundae with an E, that's the dessert.
所以当你看到这种拼写，带E的圣代，那就是甜点。
If you see it with a Y, that's the day.
如果你看到带Y的，那就是星期天。
Exactly.
没错。
So chocolate sundae, actually a very delicious dessert, but remember it's ice cream.
所以巧克力圣代，其实是一种非常美味的甜点，但记住它是冰淇淋。
That's right.
没错。
And all of these types of food, hamburger, chocolate sundae, it's called junk food.
所有这些食物，汉堡、巧克力圣代，都叫做垃圾食品。
Junk food.
垃圾食品。
Well food you know.
嗯，食物你知道。
Junk.
垃圾。
What is an example of junk, Marco?
什么是垃圾的例子，Marco？
Well something that's not good or useful anymore.
嗯，就是不再有用或不再好的东西。
So maybe you have trash that you need to get rid of, like an old TV.
比如你有一些需要扔掉的垃圾，像一台旧电视。
That's junk.
那就是垃圾。
So my mom would always say, throw away this junk.
所以我妈妈总是会说，扔掉这些垃圾。
It's stuff that you don't need.
就是你不用的东西。
So junk is things that you would throw away.
所以垃圾就是你会扔掉的东西。
Junk food is the kind of food that's not healthy for you.
垃圾食品就是对你健康不好的那种食物。
It's the food that you shouldn't eat, but it tends to be really delicious.
就是你不该吃的食物，但它往往非常美味。
That's right.
没错。
So for example, the hamburger, french fries, a chocolate sundae, all this would fall under
所以比如汉堡、薯条、巧克力圣代，这些都归入
this category of junk food.
垃圾食品这一类。
That's right.
没错。
And one of the things about junk food is that it's high in cholesterol.
垃圾食品的一个特点是它胆固醇很高。
Now what is cholesterol, Marco?
什么是胆固醇，Marco？
That's right.
没错。
So you always have to be careful.
所以你总是要小心。
Your doctor says that you shouldn't have or you have to be careful about having high cholesterol.
你的医生会说你不应该有高胆固醇，或者要小心高胆固醇。
And that's just basically, it's a type of fat that is found in animal products.
基本上，它是一种在动物产品中发现的脂肪。
So for example, beef has cholesterol and it's dangerous because it could maybe cause health
比如牛肉含有胆固醇，它很危险，因为可能会导致健康问题。
problems.
健康问题。
That's right.
没错。
So my friend needed to lower his cholesterol and his doctor told him he should eat less
所以我的朋友需要降低胆固醇，他的医生告诉他应该少吃
red meat, eat more vegetables and fruits instead.
红肉，多吃蔬菜和水果。
That's right.
没错。
So cholesterol is a, you'll see it all the time when you're shopping.
所以胆固醇是，你购物时会经常看到。
You'll see that it's low in cholesterol or no sugar or no calories, stuff like that.
你会看到低胆固醇、无糖或无卡路里之类的标签。
Exactly.
没错。
Now, a food that is very, very high in cholesterol is fried chicken, but it's also very delicious.
现在，一种胆固醇非常非常高的食物是炸鸡，但它也非常美味。
That's right.
没错。
Fried chicken.
炸鸡。
Now as you see, the first word there is fried and that means that it was cooked in hot oil.
如你所见，第一个词是“炸”，意思是用热油烹制的。
That's right.
没错。
And what's important to remember about most American fried chicken is that the chicken
关于大多数美式炸鸡，需要记住的重要一点是，鸡肉
is usually put in a batter, so like a milk, egg, flour sauce, and then it's fried.
通常裹上面糊，也就是牛奶、鸡蛋、面粉调成的酱，然后油炸。
So on the outside it's very, very crispy and salty.
所以外面非常非常酥脆和咸。
That's right.
没错。
So it's covered in like a type of bread, like a crispy bread.
所以它外面裹着一层像面包一样的东西，脆脆的面包。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
It's usually very greasy, so when you eat it, you have lots of grease on your fingers.
通常很油腻，所以吃的时候手指上会有很多油。
But one of the reasons it tastes so good is because as you say, Marco, it's fried in oil.
但味道这么好的原因之一，正如你所说，马可，是因为它在油里炸过。
That's right.
没错。
Very good.
很好。
So this is all the vocab that we have for language takeaway.
这就是我们“语言摘录”部分的所有词汇。
Let's listen to the dialogue again.
让我们再听一遍对话。
I'm hungry.
我饿了。
Let's order up something to eat.
我们点些吃的吧。
Okay, maybe we can order a soup and a salad from the restaurant down the street.
好吧，也许我们可以从街那头的餐厅点一份汤和一份沙拉。
I was thinking of getting a hamburger, fries, and a chocolate sundae.
我在想点一个汉堡、薯条和一个巧克力圣代。
You eat too much junk food.
你吃太多垃圾食品了。
That sort of stuff clogs up your arteries and is very high in cholesterol.
那种东西会堵塞你的动脉，而且胆固醇很高。
Well, I never seem to gain weight, so I don't mind.
嗯，我好像从来不会长胖，所以我不介意。
It's not only about getting fat or not, it's about being healthy.
这不只是长胖不长胖的问题，而是关于健康。
You could really have some health problems later on.
你以后真的可能会有一些健康问题。
How about pizza or maybe some fried chicken?
披萨或者炸鸡怎么样？
Better yet, let's order some hot dogs.
更好的是，我们点些热狗吧。
You're a lost cause.
你真是无可救药了。
All right, now it's time for some phrases on Fluency Builder.
好了，现在是“流利度构建”部分的一些短语。
Fluency Builder
流利度构建
So one of the first phrases is actually something that I'm excited to talk about because it
第一个短语其实是我很兴奋要讲的，因为它
comes up a lot in directions when we're giving people directions somewhere.
在指路时经常出现，当我们给别人指路时。
So one of the people in the dialogue said, we can order a soup and salad from the restaurant
对话中有一个人说，我们可以从街那头的餐厅点一份汤和沙拉。
down the street.
没错。
Right.
对。
So this is, you're basically telling the person where the restaurant is.
所以这基本上是在告诉别人餐厅的位置。
And when you say something is down the street, it means that it's nearby.
当你说某物在“down the street”时，意思是它就在附近。
It is.
是的。
It's nearby.
就在附近。
It's on the same street or it's just a few minutes walk from where you are now.
在同一条街上，或者离你现在的位置只有几分钟的步行路程。
Right, right.
对，对。
So you can say, my apartment is just down the street from this park.
所以你可以说，我的公寓就在这个公园的街那头。
So it's very close.
所以非常近。
Or you could say, I know him.
或者你可以说，我认识他。
He lived down the street from me when we were children.
我们小时候他就住在我家街那头。
Okay, so he lived really, really close to you.
好的，所以他住得离你非常非常近。
Very good.
很好。
Now, when we were talking about junk food and we were talking about how it's not healthy,
现在，当我们谈论垃圾食品以及它不健康时，
we said that junk food clogs up your arteries.
我们说垃圾食品会堵塞你的动脉。
All right.
好的。
A couple important words here to clog up arteries.
这里有几个重要的词，“clog up arteries”。
The verb to clog, what does that mean?
动词“clog”是什么意思？
Clog with a G. It means it gets in the way or obstructs it.
“Clog”带G，意思是阻碍或堵塞。
All right.
好的。
So for example, if a drain, in my sink, if a drain is clogged, the water does not go
比如，如果我水槽里的排水管堵了，水就流不
down.
下去。
Right.
对。
So the water starts to build and build and build.
所以水会越积越多。
Actually, it's very dangerous because if it comes up too much, the water will go on the
实际上，这很危险，因为如果水太多，就会流到
floor.
地板上。
But that's a drain, that's a sink.
但那是排水管，那是水槽。
If you're talking about the heart, you would say that cholesterol clogs up your arteries.
如果你在说心脏，你会说胆固醇堵塞你的动脉。
Right.
对。
So your arteries are like these tubes where blood passes.
所以你的动脉就像血液流过的管道。
And of course, if they're clogged up, then blood can't pass.
当然，如果它们被堵塞了，血液就无法通过。
That's right.
没错。
And if it's very serious, people sometimes have to have heart surgery to clear those
如果情况很严重，人们有时需要做心脏手术来清理这些
arteries to take the blockage, the clogging away from the arteries.
动脉，移除堵塞物。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So that is to clog something up or something is clogged up.
所以这就是“to clog something up”或“something is clogged up”。
Now moving on, when we were giving suggestions, we said, all right, well, how about pizza
现在继续，当我们提建议时，我们说，好吧，披萨
or maybe some fried chicken?
或者炸鸡怎么样？
Better yet, let's order some hot dogs.
更好的是，我们点些热狗吧。
All right.
好的。
Now this is a great phrase, as you say, Marco, for offering a suggestion.
正如你所说，马可，这是一个很好的提建议的短语。
You could say, I think we should eat hamburgers.
你可以说，我觉得我们应该吃汉堡。
Better yet.
更好的是。
Okay.
好的。
So what does this mean?
所以这是什么意思？
This means I actually had a better idea while I was telling you my other idea.
这意味着我在告诉你另一个想法时，实际上想到了一个更好的主意。
So it can be used in the middle of a sentence like here, right?
所以它可以像这里一样用在句子中间，对吧？
It's kind of like an interjection.
这有点像是一个感叹词。
Better yet, you know what?
更好的是，你知道吗？
Let's get some pizza.
我们去买点披萨吧。
So it's better than the idea you just had.
所以这比你刚才的想法更好。
Right.
对。
So let's go swimming.
那我们去游泳吧。
Better yet, let's go play basketball.
更好的是，我们去打篮球吧。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
So towards the end, our friend said, you know what?
所以最后，我们的朋友说，你知道吗？
You're a lost cause.
你真是无可救药了。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
What does this phrase mean?
这个短语是什么意思？
You're a lost cause.
你真是无可救药了。
It's an interesting phrase.
这是一个有趣的短语。
This is basically a way of saying I can do nothing to change you.
这基本上是在说，我无法改变你。
You have a bad habit or you have this bad quality and anything I do, it's not going
你有一个坏习惯或者这种坏品质，我做什么都
to help.
没用。
Right.
对。
So something that is a lost cause, it means it's hopeless, helpless.
所以“lost cause”指的是毫无希望、无可救药的东西。
That's right.
没错。
I cannot do anything to change it.
我做什么都无法改变它。
Okay.
好的。
All right.
好吧。
A lot of great vocab here.
这里有很多好词汇。
Let's listen to the dialogue one last time.
让我们最后再听一遍对话。
I'm hungry.
我饿了。
Let's order up something to eat.
我们点些吃的吧。
Okay.
好的。
Maybe we can order a soup and a salad from the restaurant down the street.
也许我们可以从街那头的餐厅点一份汤和一份沙拉。
I was thinking of getting a hamburger, fries and a chocolate sundae.
我在想要一个汉堡、薯条和巧克力圣代。
You eat too much junk food.
你吃太多垃圾食品了。
That sort of stuff clogs up your arteries and is very high in cholesterol.
那种东西会堵塞你的动脉，而且胆固醇很高。
Well I never seem to gain weight so I don't mind.
嗯，我好像从来不会发胖，所以我不介意。
It's not only about getting fat or not.
这不只是关于胖不胖的问题。
It's about being healthy.
这是关于健康的问题。
You could really have some health problems later on.
你以后真的可能会有一些健康问题。
How about pizza or maybe some fried chicken?
披萨或者炸鸡怎么样？
Better yet, let's order some hot dogs.
更好的是，我们点些热狗吧。
You're a lost cause.
你真是无可救药了。
All right.
好吧。
So talking about junk food, we took a look at cholesterol.
说到垃圾食品，我们提到了胆固醇。
Now apparently not all cholesterol is bad.
现在显然不是所有胆固醇都是坏的。
That's right.
没错。
There are two kinds of cholesterol, HDLs and LDLs.
有两种胆固醇，高密度脂蛋白和低密度脂蛋白。
One kind is good for you and the other kind is bad for you.
一种对你有益，另一种对你有害。
So it's important when you talk to your doctor, you ask your doctor if the bad cholesterol
所以当你和医生交谈时，重要的是要问医生你的坏胆固醇
is high for you.
是否偏高。
Because if it's the good cholesterol that's high, you're probably not going to experience
因为如果是好胆固醇偏高，你可能不会出现
health problems.
健康问题。
But if you have really high bad cholesterol, then that's something that you should think
但如果你坏胆固醇真的很高，那你在吃东西和选择食物时
about when you eat and when you choose the kinds of foods that you eat.
就需要考虑一下了。
So usually, my doctor always used to tell me to not eat so many eggs because eggs are
所以通常，我的医生总是告诉我不要吃太多鸡蛋，因为鸡蛋
high in cholesterol.
胆固醇高。
That's right.
没错。
Red meat and eggs and salty foods I think.
红肉、鸡蛋和咸的食物，我想。
But generally speaking, I think it's good just to eat a lot of vegetables and to balance
但总的来说，我认为多吃蔬菜并平衡
out your diet.
饮食是好的。
So vegetables don't really even have cholesterol.
所以蔬菜其实不含胆固醇。
No.
不。
They have high cholesterol and I think they also have a lot of vitamins and minerals that
它们胆固醇高，而且我认为它们还含有很多你身体需要的
your body needs.
维生素和矿物质。
It's very, very interesting because actually all food that is usually very, very delicious
非常非常有趣，因为实际上所有通常非常非常美味的食物
is high in cholesterol or high in calories.
都胆固醇高或热量高。
It's bad for you.
对你有害。
It's basically junk food.
基本上就是垃圾食品。
Yeah.
是的。
So potato chips, hot dogs, pizza, fried chicken, all of these delicious foods, they're all
所以薯片、热狗、披萨、炸鸡，所有这些美味的食物，都被
considered junk food and they're all really bad for you.
认为是垃圾食品，而且都对你非常有害。
That's right.
没错。
So that's a very interesting topic.
所以这是一个非常有趣的话题。
Now there are certain local types of junk food that people consider to be junk food.
现在有一些当地类型的垃圾食品，人们认为它们是垃圾食品。
Like for example, if you go maybe to the Middle East, you'll have the wraps, right?
比如，如果你去中东，你会看到卷饼，对吧？
That could be considered a type of junk food.
那可以被视为一种垃圾食品。
I guess.
我想是的。
Yeah.
是的。
Because it's fast, it's greasy.
因为它快，而且油腻。
It is pretty greasy.
确实挺油腻的。
All this delicious, like a shawarma wrap.
所有这些美味的，比如沙威玛卷饼。
Exactly.
没错。
So maybe you can let us know what local type of junk food you have.
所以也许你可以告诉我们，你们当地有什么类型的垃圾食品。
This is mostly American, burgers, fries, hot dogs.
这主要是美式的，汉堡、薯条、热狗。
Exactly.
没错。
What is it in your country?
你们国家有什么呢？
Let us know, our website is EnglishPod.com.
告诉我们吧，我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
We'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Bye.
再见。
Okay, bye.
好的，再见。